Guide to the Cornell University football motion pictures movies, videos, and film,1927-1990.
Cornell University football motion pictures movies, videos, and film,1927-1990
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University football motion pictures,
1927-1995.
40-2-2205
Cornell University.
923+ film reels (22.4 cubic ft.); c. 22+ video cassettes (12 cubic ft.)
Movie Film.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Films and videos of Cornell University football games.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Films and videos of Cornell University football games.
Also, "The Big Red Machine: Exciting play-by-play highlights of Cornell's 1971 Ivy League Championship season narrated by Jay Levine."
Digitization of films can be arranged if requested.
Cornell University.; Cornell University--Football.; Cornell University--Athletics.; Football.; Motion pictures.; Videotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Some films labeled "highlights" may refer to a single game.
University of Pennsylvania Archives has film of all Penn-Cornell games.
See also Cornell University Football Game Highlights, #40-2-1000, for some 1950 and 1951 reels. Also Hunter Ripley Rawlings Papers, #3-13-2843, for 1991 highlights.
See also Howard Schuck papers, #37-5-2629, for more information on the team, particularly on the Ohio game of 1939.
See also Cornell University Museum Items, #47-7-1948.
See also Big Red Band Records, #37-6-3112.
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a copy of the printed finding aid. Use this link to see the list of all the films, over 1000.
- DVDs Available of the following.See above link for all films.
  - Cornell vs. Dartmouth, 1928 (F-369 by Allan H. Morgensen), 764 (Box DVD Box 2)
  - Cornell vs. Alfred, 1936 1 of 2 (Box 22, Reel 645), 20 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Alfred, 1936 2 of 2 (Box 22, Reel #544) Nice shots of Schoellkopf stadium crescent crowd, 21 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Ohio, 1939, (Reel #311, #312, #309, transfered from V-67) Shows marching band, 16 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Ohio, 1939, shorter alternate version of above, 41 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Syracuse, 1939, part 1 (Box 11, Reel #310) color, 134 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Syracuse, 1939, part 2 (Box 11, Reel #308) color, 134 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Dartmouth, 1939, part 1 (Box 11, Reel #315), 134 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Dartmouth, 1939, part 2 (Box 11, Reel #316), 134 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Dartmouth, 1939, part 3 (Box 7, Reel #207), 134 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Dartmouth, 1939, part 4 (Box 41, Reel #1097), 134 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Colgate, 1939, (V-226, Reel #251), 525 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Columbia, 1939, (V-227, Reels #236, #206), 525 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1939, (V-230, Reel #481), 525 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Dartmouth, 1940, fifth down play, 134 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Ohio State, 1940, part 1 (Box 11), 131 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Ohio State, 1940, part 2 (Box 11), 131 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Ohio State, 1940, part 3 (Box 11), 131 (Box 62)
    Shows Cornell Big Red marching band performance and tearing down the field goal at end.
  - Cornell vs. Ohio State, 1940, part 1 (Box 11, Reel #319) color, 132 (Box 62)
    Also includes photos of the players and team roster. Amazing panning shots show a packed to capacity Schoellkopf stadium and you can see the cheerleaders and marching bands perform at halftime as well. Some of the footage in the middle is out of order.Some of the footage is out of order in the middle.
  - Cornell vs. Ohio State, 1940, part 2 (Box 11, Reel #320) color, 132 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1940, part 1 (Box 11, Reel #318), 133 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1940, part 2 (Box 11, Reel #322), 133 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1940, part 3 (Box 11, Reel #321), 133 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1940, part 5 (Box 11, Reel #325), 133 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Army, 1942, part 1 (Box 11, Reel #301), 781 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Army, 1942, part 2 (Box 18, Reel #520), 781 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Army, 1942, part 3 (Box 11, Reel #302), 781 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Princeton, 1946, parts 1-3 (Box 21, Reel #632, 634, 635, V-63), 521 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1954, (V-230, Reel #314), 1939; 525 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Brown, 1955, part 1 (Box 17, Reel #506), 124 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Brown, 1955, part 2 (Box 10, Reel #279), 124 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Brown, 1955, part 3 (Box 10, Reel #281), 124 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Brown, 1956, part 1 (Box 14, Reel #417), 125 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Brown, 1956, part 2 (Box 14, Reel #418), 125 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Brown, 1956, part 3 (Box 14, Reel #398), 125 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Brown, 1957 (3 Reels), 45 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Brown, 1958 (3 Reels), 46 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Columbia, 1964 (Box 27, Reel #797) 2nd Quarter, 860 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Columbia, 1964 (Box 6, Reel #153) 3rd Quarter, 860 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Columbia, 1964 (Box 6, Reel #159) 4th Quarter, 860 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Dartmouth, 1964 (Box 6, Reel #158) 1st Quarter, 860 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Dartmouth, 1964 (Box 6, Reel #164) 3rd Quarter, 860 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Dartmouth, 1964 (Box 6, Reel #154) 4th Quarter, 860 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1964 (Box 16, Reel #468) 1st Quarter, 981 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1964 (Box 12, Reel #340) 2nd Quarter, 981 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1964 (Box 12, Reel #344) 3rd Quarter, 981 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1964 (Box 12, Reel #341) 4th Quarter, 981 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Princeton, 1964 (Box 26, Reel #753) 1st Quarter, 981 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Princeton, 1964 (Box 26, Reel #754) 2nd Quarter, 981 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Princeton, 1964 (Box 26, Reel #760) 3rd Quarter, 981 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Princeton, 1964 (Box 26, Reel #759) 4th Quarter, 981 (Box 62)
  - Cornell Football Highlights, 1979, color and sound, includes clip of honoring the 1939 and 1940 Cornell team at halftime of the Yale game., 480 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1988 (Box 28, Reel #809) 1st Half Offense, 126 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1988 (Box 28, Reel #810) 2nd Half Offense, 126 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1988 (Box 28, Reel #811)1st Half Defense, 126 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1988 (Box 28, Reel #812) 2nd Half Defense, 126 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Penn, 1988 (Box 28, Reel #813) Special Teams, 126 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Brown, 1989, 481 (Box 62)
  - Cornell at. Lehigh, 1995, Special Teams (Box 51, Tape 1366), 712 (Box 62)
  - Cornell at. Brown, 1995, Special Teams (Box 51, Tape 1373), 712 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Yale, 1995, Special Teams (Box 52, Tape 1414), 712 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Columbia, Special Teams 1995 (Box 52, Tape 1420), 712 (Box 62)
  - Cornell vs. Columbia, 1995, complete game, endzone camera (Box 52, Tape 1423), 712 (Box 62)
- The Big Red Machine: Exciting play-by-play highlights of Cornell's 1971 Ivy League Championship season narrated by Jay Levine, LP record. Features Ed Marinaro., 1201